Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1830-1839., 203 items. (Box 2-3)
    - Letters, 1836., 25 items. (Box-folder 3:47-71)
      - Cha[rle]s Campbell, Glencoe, Alabama to [Elizabeth Campbell Maben], 17 June 1836., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:54)
        He has been sick and confined to bed. News of crops. Cousin Alfred Aglett dies. Speaks of incompatibility of his headaches with teaching profession.
      - E[lizabeth] M. Henley, Chota, Tennessee to Charles Campbell, Tuscumbia, Alabama, 25 June 1836., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:55)
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 25 June 1836., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:56)
        Inquires after her family. Trouble with her eyes. Weather poor, wheat crop failing.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Chota, Tennessee to [Elizabeth Campbell Maben], 20 August 1836., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:57)
        Informs her of his intention to marry Elvira N. Callaway of Toqua before end of September. His intention to return to Virginia then. Inquires after health of her child.
      - C[harles] [Campbell], Chota, [Tennessee] to E[lvira Callaway],23 August 1836., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:58)
        Looking forward to their wedding, September 13.
      - C[harles] [Campbell], Chota, [Tennessee] to E[lvira Callaway],25 August 1836., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:59)
        Looking forward to their marriage.
      - E[lizabeth] M. [Maben], Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Tuscumbia, Alabama, [? September 1836]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:60)
        Social news. Spring arriving. Mother has left but she sees father every day.
      - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Petersburg, to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, September 1836., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:61)
        She has been sick in bed. She is pleased to hear of his marriage. She is very busy taking care of her child [Jane], husband, and house. Mr. Maben has also been ill. Aleck goes to College in November.
        Postscript: 2 pages. ALS. A[lexander] S[potswood] Campbell, to Charles [Campbell]. Hopes Charles will return before he goes to College.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Chota, Tennessee to Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 4 September 1836., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:62)
        Informs her of his impending marriage and trip to Virginia. Description of his bride.
      - M[ary] K. Henley, Chota, [Tennessee] to Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 11 September 1836., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:62A)
        Charles Campbell will be leaving for Virginia in two days to bring his wife home; would like to visit Virginia. Elizabeth J. Henley to Mildred W. Campbell. Best wishes.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to H[enry] Barnard,26 September 1836., 3 pages. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 3:63)
        Summarizes his travels in the West for the last 2 years. Tells of his marriage. He is still not very well, but has done some writing and may attempt to publish some of it.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to A[rthur] H[azelrigg] Henley,25 October 1836., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:64)
        Difficult seven day journey from Knoxville to Petersburg; Petersburg vastly improved since last visit and $200,000 subscribed for a railroad to E. Tennessee; wife Elvira happy and attends church more; Synod will meet in Petersburg next week; has found some Revolutionary War papers and six George Washington letters.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Arthur Henley, Chota, E. Tennessee, 28 October 1836., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:65)
        Took seven days to travel from Knoxville to Petersburg and was a difficult journey; Petersburg is vastly improved and is planning to build a railroad to E. Tennessee for which they have a $200,000 subscription; Betty lives in a fine house and her husband is worth $100,000 but is a tobacco speculator so may go broke; brother Aleck going to Princeton; wife Elvira happy; synod meets in Petersburg next week; child abandoned on a doorstep in town and Charles Campbell's mother subpoenaed as a witness in the case; thinks of moving west to Illinois or Missouri when the estate settled.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to [Henry] Barnard,2 November 1836., 1 page. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 3:66)
        Has decided not to go to New York and so will not be able to meet him. Has abandoned plan of publishing some of his work.
      - Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 12 November 1836., 4 pages. Signature clipped. ALS. (Box-folder 3:67)
        Expresses interest in his research in Revolutionary documents and letters. Reports the death of a friend, and other social news. Says that Van Buren was almost defeated in Connecticut.
      - Charles Campbell, Norfolk, [Virginia] to Elvira [Campbell],[Petersburg, Virginia], 18 November 1836., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:68)
        Describes his trip to Norfolk; went with Mr. Ruffin to Suffolk; will go by boat to Philadelphia; will return in 10 days; spent an evening with Barraud.
      - Elizabeth Henley, Chota, Tennessee to Elvira A. Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 25 November 1836., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:69)
        Misses her company. Also, a note from Mary Henley. Misses her.
      - [Rev. W. S. Plumer] (penciled in), Richmond, to [Charles Campbell], 12 December 1836., 1 page. Autograph clipped. AL. (Box-folder 3:70)
        Charles Campbell's letter received, has attended to matter. Suggests not to send any piece on which have not done his best.
      - Charles Campbell to O. B. Barraud, Petersburg, 19 December 1836., 3 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 3:71)
        Letter explains a possible business speculation in a cotton seed oil business (Smith & Follett, owners).
    - Letters, 1837., 37 items. (Box-folder 3:72-108)
      - Charles Campbell to Aunt, [c. 1837]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:72)
        Elvira needs assistance, asks for Mrs. Paisley to come immediately.
      - Alexander S. Campbell to Charles [Campbell], [1837?]. (Box-folder 3:73)
        Studies going well except for mathematics. Gave first College speech on "Love of Country." Glad to have sister Betty write to him.
      - Account of Mr. Campbell with Boswell Jefferson, 3 January 1837., 1 page. MS. (Box-folder 3:74)
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Mr. Anderson, Yorktown, 18 January 1837., 1 page. ADfS. (Box-folder 3:75)
        Campbell about to publish short work on Virginia history in Southern Literary Messenger. Requests information from Anderson on James City and Gloucester Counties, Yorktown and siege.
      - Elizabeth Aylett Keller, Tuscumbia, [Alabama] to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, 13 February 1837., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:76)
        News of the Female Academy she is attending; family gossip.
      - E[lizabeth] M. M[aben] to Charles Campbell, Chota, East Tennessee, [27] February [1837]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:77)
        News of Father's business and her reading. Mr. Maben thinking of going to Texas, but may put it off. He is going to England next year. News of Aleck in College.
        Postscript: 2 pages. ALS. [Mildred W. Campbell] to [Charles Campbell]. Social news.
      - W[illia]m M. Campbell, St. Charles, Missouri to Charles Campbell, Chota, Monroe County, Tennessee, 5 March 1837. (Box-folder 3:78)
        Has been in Missouri 7 years; Is a member of the general assembly; Lists Missouri resources.
      - [Charles Campbell], Toqua, Monroe County, Tennessee to [Elizabeth Aylett Keller?] [Tuscumbia, Alabama], 7 March 1837., L. 2 pages. (Box-folder 3:79)
        Has gotten married; brother and sister well; father still selling books; thinking of moving to Missouri.
      - Tho[ma]s C. Batte, Charles County Missouri, to Charles Campbell, Monroe County, Chota P.O., East Tennessee, 10 March 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:80)
        Suggests Charles Campbell move to his state but visit before he decides doing so. Cost of government priced land is increasing. Discussion of the climate.
      - Elvira N. Campbell, Toqua, Tennessee to [Mrs. Mildred W. Campbell], [Petersburg], 16 March 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:81)
        Speaks of possibility of building a house; Mr. Campbell's (Charles?) like of farming.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Chota, Tennessee to Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 18 March [1837]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:82)
        Informs her of land he has bought and his intentions to build on it.
      - Elizabeth Keller, Tuscumbia [Alabama] to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, 31 March 1837. (Box-folder 3:83)
        Hopes Henleys will visit wants to meet Charles Campbell's wife; news of her studies; news of her brothers and sisters.
      - Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, 7 April 1837., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:84)
        Family news. Effects of worsening economic conditions on various neighbors.
      - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, [19 April 1837]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:85)
        Were visited by Aleck. Going to Richmond shortly. News of Aleck in college.
      - A[lexander] M[oore] Keller, Tuscumbia [Alabama] to Aunt, 8 May 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:86)
        Death of his father; Lavinia [Moore?] being sent to the aunt.
      - Charles Campbell, Toqua Creek to Elizabeth Aylett Keller, Tuscumbia, Alabama, 15 May 1837., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:87)
        Family news; is living in a log house; corn scarce; has heard report of low cotton prices.
      - J[ohn] W[ilson] Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to Charles [Campbell], 8 June 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:88)
        John Wilson Campbell has been unwell; businesses are all doing badly banks, railroads, etc., and therefore will be unable to help Charles Campbell out; fever to move west has died out; Mabens spoke of traveling north, but currency troubles make travel difficult.
      - [Charles Campbell], Toqua, Tennessee to [Thomas W.] White,12 June 1837., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:89)
        Was happy to see recent article of his appear in the Southern Literary Messenger. Points out that some of his sentences were made to stand alone as paragraphs. Encloses an order in which he wants future articles published.
      - Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, 4 July 1837., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:90)
        Her recovery from influenza. Mention of a recent religious convention.
      - [Elvira C. Campbell] Toqua to [Mildred W. Campbell], [Petersburg], 6 July 1837., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:91)
        They have moved and have built two cabins and a stable. Hard times, everything scarce. Charles sick from exertion of building.
      - Alexander S. Campbell, Princeton, New Jersey to Charles Campbell, Chota, Tennessee, 12 July [1837]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:92)
        Has sent him college catalogue. Describes 4th of July festivities. Requests suggestions for senior speech topics.
      - [Charles Campbell], Toqua to [Alexander S. Campbell]. 29 July 1837., 2 pages/2 pages. Fragment. ADF-AL. (Box-folder 3:93)
        Announces birth of his son, named Callaway. Farming going well. Suggestions for Aleck's "senior speech": the lights and shadows of a student's life, description of Princeton, on the death of Major Andre, defense of U.S. policy toward Indians.
      - Charles Campbell, Toqua, Tennessee to [Mrs. Mildred W. Campbell], [Petersburg], 1 August 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:94)
        Announces death of his wife, Elvira, of child-bed fever; leaving him and his child. He has given the child to Elvira's sister.
      - Alexander S. Campbell, Na[s]sau Hall, to [John W. Campbell], [Petersburg], [September 1837]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:95)
        Received and is saddened by news of Elvira Callaway Campbell's death. Session over at end of month; he will return home then.
      - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Fauquier, to Mrs. [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, 1 September [1837]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:96)
        Received news of Elvira Campbell's death. Her family all well, going to Winchester next week and returning ca. first of October.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to [Callaway], 8 September 1837., 2 pages. Incomplete. AL. (Box-folder 3:97)
        Wants her to bring his child to Petersburg.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to cousin, 12 September 1837., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:98)
        Mourns death of his wife; regrets leaving his child.
      - William M. Campbell, St. Charles, Missouri, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 27 September 1837., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:99)
        Sympathy at death of Charles Campbell's wife; uncertain about Charles Campbell starting a literary paper; his section of the country lacks money.
      - [Charles Campbell] to [Mary K. Henley?], October 1837. (Box-folder 3:100)
        Misses his child; suffers from headache and depression; family news.
      - Betty [Elizabeth M. Henley], Chota, Tennessee to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 8 October 1837., 4 pages. Charles Campbell's ALS. (Box-folder 3:101)
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia]. to Lavinia M[cPheeters] Brown, Raleigh, North Carolina, 16 October 1837., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:102)
        Sad she is in ill health; his wife dead of "fever and derangement;" expects his headache will never end; his wife's family trying to keep his son.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Elizabeth Keller, Tuscumbia, Alabama, 30 October 1837., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:103)
        Sympathy on death of her father; reports death of his wife and birth of his son; his son taken from him; brother Aleck going to Princeton; his headache continues; melancholy continues.
      - Lavinia M[cPheeters] Brown, Raleigh, [North Carolina] to Charles Campbell, November 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:104)
        Has been sick; thinks Charles Campbell should continue with engineering; would like Betty to visit when the railroad is done; does not appear to be sick because she has a nervous disease.
      - [?], Mobile to Charles Cam[pbe]ll, Petersburg, Virginia, 30 November 1837., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:105)
        About buying a slave; yellow fever epidemic; asks Charles Campbell's mother to visit his wife.
      - Alexander Moore Keller, Tuscumbia [Alabama] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 2 December 1837., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:106)
        Has visited relatives at Chota.
      - R. M. Anderson to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 8 December 1837., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:107)
        On guardianship of Charles Campbell's son Callaway; legal advice on the guardianship; Mr. Callaway has not filed a legal motion to take over the guardianship; advises Charles Campbell to file a motion on it in Federal Court.
      - [A. M. Keller], Tuscumbia, [Alabama] to Charles Campbell; Petersburg, Virginia, 27 December 1837., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:108)
        Courtship; Family news.
    - Letters, 1838., 22 items. (Box-folder 3:109-130)
      - Lavinia Moore, Petersburg, [Virginia] to "Mother" [A. J. Dickson], [c. 1838]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:109)
        Is going to Mrs. Gray's school; brother William has grown a lot.
      - [Alexander S. Campbell], Princeton, to [John W. Campbell], Petersburg, [1838?]., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:110)
        Stopped in Washington and went to House and Senate. Describes burning of Abolitionists Hall in Philadelphia. Has read piece in New Yorker by Charles.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to [Thomas H.] Williamson,6 January 1838., 3 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 3:111)
        Would like to work on railroad for health reasons.
      - A[nne] E[velina] H[enley], Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 6 January 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:112)
        News of his son; is teaching her younger children; Uncle Spotswood has rheumatism.
      - Henry Barnard Hartford, Connecticut to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 7 January 1838., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:113)
        Difficulty in settling his father's estate prevents him from coming to Virginia. He greatly enjoyed spending New Years Day in New York. Tells him of books he has been reading.
      - [Otway B. Barraud], Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, 13 January 1838., 3 pages. Signature clipped. AL. (Box-folder 3:114)
        Extends his condolences. Encourages him to go into editing newspaper or magazine, particularly perhaps the Messenger, believing Campbell would do a better job than White. At same time, Barraud excuses himself from joining in the venture.
      - [Thomas Williamson], Westham to [Charles] Campbell, 17 January 1838., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:115)
        Can use him for a reference; Job opening for a surveyor for a canal.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 20 January 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:116)
        Has not yet received package sent. Will send $30 next week. Invites her for visit.
      - [Illegible], Petersburg, to Samuel Houston, President of Texas, 22 January 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:117)
        Letter of recommendation for Frederick Robbins.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to [Alexander S. Campbell], 23 January 1838., 3 pages. Fragment. AL. (Box-folder 3:118)
        Father has been nominated for office of Collector; will soon control patronage involved. He is about to undertake engineering job on James River. Mentions other political matters: Canada, Texas bill.
      - [William M. Campbell], St. Charles, Missouri to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 15 April 1838., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:119)
        "Bitter effects of the bank veto" which "deranged Commerce"; asks for Petersburg information for Hannah Rochester.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Princeton, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, June 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:120)
        Has seen subsequent articles in New Yorker by Charles. News of Princeton. Has been reading newspapers, etc.
      - A. J. Dickson, to "daughter" [Maria Lavinia Moore], Petersburg, Virginia, 8 June 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:121)
        Misses her; glad she is going to school; hopes she will not hurry into marriage; misses William.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to [Alexander Campbell], [Princeton], 1 July 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:122)
        Family and social news. Politics: Speaks of struggles in House over subtreasury and banks. Talk of split in Whig Party.
      - Alexander S. Campbell, Princeton, New Jersey, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 9 July 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:123)
        Describes 4th of July celebration mentions opinions of Literary Messenger and New Yorker. Will write to father.
      - [A. M. Keller], Buzzard Roost, Alabama to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 4 September 1838., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:124)
        Announces his engagement and lists fiancee's accomplishments; she is Irish and named Jane E. Sheegog.
      - Cha[rle]s Campbell, Chota, to [Alexander S. Campbell], 10 September 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:125)
        His visit to Cherokee Camp described. Speaks of legal difficulties in obtaining possession of his son. Headaches very bad.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mrs. Mildred Campbell, Petersburg, 20 October 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:126)
        Inquires for news of her trip. Intends to visit her, at time of fair and church meeting. Describes sad condition of her own parish.
      - Joseph B. Gravely, Breckenridge, to Ch[arles] Campbell, 23 October 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:127)
        A subscription letter for 1st ed. of History of Virginia.
      - Betty [Elizabeth M. Henley], Chota, Tennessee to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 9 November 1838., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:128)
        News of Charles Campbell's son; soldiers pursuing Indians; family news.
      - [?] W. Fisher, East Netel [?] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 26 November 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:129)
        Thinks Upshur manuscript still exists.
      - Ed[mund] Ruffin and Jos[eph] A. White, Petersburg to [Charles Campbell], 29 December 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:130)
        They ask him to give one or more lectures before the Petersburg Lyceum.
    - Letters, 1839., 24 items. (Box-folder 3:131-154)
      - [Charles Campbell?] to T. T. Campbell, [c. 1839]., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:131)
        Discusses taking of depositions in his case to gain guardianship of his son.
      - R. Baird, Richmond, [Virginia] to Mr. and Mrs. John W[ilson] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 16 February 1839., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:132)
        Will preach in the Presbyterian Church about France; will preach in Petersburg Monday and asks John Wilson Campbell to announce it; will lecture on Evangelical religion in France.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Mrs. McGuire, 8 March 1839., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 3:133)
        Thanks her for a letter.
      - M[ary] K. Henley, Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 13 April [C. 1839]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:134)
        News of Charles Campbell's son; family news. Betty [Elizabeth M. Henley] to Charles Campbell. News of his son.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] Henley, Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 22 June 1839., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:135)
        Describes legal maneuvers over guardianship of Charles Campbell's son; only ground Charles Campbell could lose the case on would be his insanity, but Arthur Hazelrigg Henley Does not expect that tactic to succeed; Charles Campbell's son is well; Family news. M[ary] K. Henley to Charles Campbell. Gossip has ruined Mrs. Russell's reputation; Uncle Spotswood happy with his new home at Aunt Eliza's; Charles Campbell's son is learning to talk.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Mr. Tarver, 28 June 1839., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 3:136)
        Has not written to Lavinia Moore's mother because some of her views are "indiscreet and improper"; thinks Mr. Tarver will do all that is proper for Lavinia; Lavinia is well.
      - Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 3 July 1839., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:137)
        He has been kept extremely busy with his activities of establishing the Board of Education in Connecticut. Gives news of mutual friends. He is active in founding of Connecticut Historical Society.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Mr. [Thomas] White,19 July 1839., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 3:138)
        Has some historic letters he would like published in the Messenger.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] Henley, Chota, Tennessee, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 20 July 1839., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:139)
        Reports on progress of Charles Campbell's legal attempts to gain guardianship of his son, all testimony has been in Charles Campbell's favor; Charles Campbell's son healthy; Arthur Hazelrigg Henley. Has a "nervous affection" in his right hand which prevents him from writing well; N. Byers swore in court that he saw Charles Campbell "in a passion" once.
      - Th[omas] W. White, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 20 July 1839., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:140)
        Thanks him for Col. Bland's letter, which will be published in the September issue of the Messenger. He is flooded with contributions to the Messenger: he has more than he can publish. Apologizes for not being able to publish more of Campbell's material, but hopes to do better in the future.
      - Mr. [?] Cocke, to Alex[ander] S. Campbell, Petersburg, 21 July 1839., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:141)